<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Good poem Archives - Tin Hay</title>
	<atom:link href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/category/culture/good-poem/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/category/culture/good-poem/</link>
	<description>Một trang web mới sử dụng WordPress</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 02:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Mr. Do&#8217;s poem Paper</title>
		<link>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/mr-dos-poem/</link>
					<comments>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/mr-dos-poem/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[qt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 03:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Good poem]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/?p=61</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Every year the peach blossoms bloom, I see the old man&#8230;&#8221; In Vietnam, related to the theme of Tet, perhaps there is no poem as widely popular as the poem &#8220;Mr. Do&#8221; by Vu Dinh Lien. (1913-96) Each year the...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/mr-dos-poem/">Mr. Do&#8217;s poem Paper</a> appeared first on <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en">Tin Hay</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Every year the peach blossoms bloom, I see the old man&#8230;&#8221; In Vietnam, related to the theme of Tet, perhaps there is no poem as widely popular as the poem &#8220;Mr. Do&#8221; by Vu Dinh Lien. (1913-96)<br />
Each year the flowers peach blossom<br />
That his old toys<br />
Paper presented red ink<br />
Inside a crowded street over<br />
How many tenants wrote<br />
User praise switch plates<br />
“Hypal flowers have strokes<br />
As phoenix dragon dance&#8221;.<br />
But every year it&#8217;s absent<br />
Where the tenant write this?<br />
Red paper petal sad;<br />
Research toner left in grief&#8230;<br />
He sat there map,<br />
Passers nobody or.<br />
Leaves fall on the paper;<br />
In addition to rain giời dust.<br />
Peach bloom again this year,<br />
Not seeing his old toys.<br />
Those who live forever<br />
Where soul now ?<br />
In the first two stanzas of the poem, the author uses purely narrative style, just telling the story, which is quite a normal story, like a habit, a familiar rhythm: &#8220;Every year&#8230; see&#8230;&#8221; It&#8217;s not surprising at all. But the author still cannot hide his aesthetic emotions at what he sees every year. Regarding the coming of Tet, people have many ways to say: either directly, concisely like &#8220;Tet is coming&#8221; or &#8220;spring is coming&#8221;; Or choose a typical image of Tet, of spring like a swallow, like new sunshine, like blooming peach blossoms. Vu Dinh Lien chose the last option. It&#8217;s also nothing new. The flute is different. There have been countless people who have written like that: peach blossoms and winter and spring winds. Anyway, Vu Dinh Lien&#8217;s choice is also very meaningful: &#8220;Every year peach blossoms bloom&#8221; is chosen to introduce spring in its most beautiful corner. In that corner, next to the peach blossoms, seemingly blooming with the peach blossoms, is an old man with black ink and red paper and perhaps, a head of white hair.</p>
<p>Mr. Tu &#8220;blooms&#8221; with peach blossoms, and with peach blossoms, Mr. Tu becomes a symbol of spring: in the bustling crowd of people walking on the street enjoying spring, there was a large number of people stopping next to him. him, contemplating his hand moving the pen nimbly &#8220;like a phoenix dancing with a dragon&#8221; on cashew paper. Admiring that hand, they used the word: &#8220;flower hand.&#8221; With that word &#8220;flower hand&#8221;, people no longer consider him as a disciple, a teacher, or a person who spreads the words of saints and sages, but consider him as an artist. The aesthetic aspect of him stands out, overwhelming the educational aspect.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the word &#8220;flower&#8221; in &#8220;hand flower&#8221; cannot help but evoke the word &#8220;peach blossom&#8221; in the first sentence: it seems that, when spring comes, there are two types of flowers blooming at the same time, one in the garden and one in the garden. the master&#8217;s hand.</p>
<p>In the resonance between the peach blossom and the grandfather, there is something a bit paradoxical and ironic: the peach blossom is a new flower and the person is an old person, &#8220;the old monk.&#8221; Behind him, therefore, is a whole past, a whole tradition. “Every year&#8230; see…” When does “every year” mean? Maybe not very long. In the past, when asking for parallel sentences, including Tet couplets, people probably went to the homes of monks or retired academicians &#8211; as in the case of Nguyen Khuyen, who made countless parallel sentences that are still available today. be reminded. The phenomenon of &#8220;displaying Chinese ink on red paper / on a crowded street,&#8221; if I guess correctly, is just one of the manifestations of the trend of commercialization and urbanization that has occurred in Vietnam since the late 19th century. when Vietnam was invaded by France. It is a new profession for old people. This irony contains a historical tragedy. It reminds us of the fact that, along with foreign invasion, Vietnamese society was completely turned upside down, which, directly related to the fate of our grandfather, was the decline of Confucianism. That decline leads to the loss of a whole class of people who, at one time, we still considered symbols of traditional Vietnamese culture. “There&#8217;s nothing wrong with the word grapes. &#8220;I&#8217;m tired, even I&#8217;m lying down,&#8221; Tu Xuong once cried out, aching and heartbroken. In that chaotic situation, students flocked to learn Western language. He had to say goodbye to the school, the holy words, the literary reviews and reading sessions to accept the sad way of making a living by writing couplets for Tet every spring.</p>
<p>Luckily for him, the change in cultural traditions is often slower than the change in history, politics, society, and the educational and examination systems. The masses still have the habit of respecting Chinese characters, at least during Tet days. That gave him, on the one hand, a way to make a living, and on the other hand, he still had friends who knew how to appreciate his talent, even if they were friends passing by. That enthusiastic enjoyment made his ironic seat on the sidewalk feel warm.</p>
<p>The first two stanzas, therefore, not only speak of the resonance and harmony between humans and nature but also of the interconnection between humans. The monk did not sit alone with the peach blossoms. Besides him, there are also loyal customers. Around them, spring is fragrant and colorful. Pretty. And fun. Joy overflows into the storyteller&#8217;s words: his voice is loud and strong with words starting with the crisp consonant &#8220;d&#8221; (peach, do, red, east&#8230;); He spoke quickly, told in one go, without stopping, very enthusiastic, full of passion, very excited: in two verses, each of four lines, in terms of grammar, in fact, it was just one sentence, one just sentence:</p>
<p>Every year peach blossoms bloom again</p>
<p>I saw an old man displaying red ink and paper on a crowded street.</p>
<p>Many people wrote notes praising his talent: &#8220;The palm flowers have features like a phoenix dancing and a dragon flying.&#8221;<a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/how-many-friends-do-you-have/">https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/how-many-friends-do-you-have/</a></p>
<p>A <a title="Developing country" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Developing_country">developing country</a> with a lower-middle-income economy, Vietnam is one of the <a title="List of countries by real GDP growth rate" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_real_GDP_growth_rate">fastest-growing economies</a> of the 21st century. Vietnam has <a title="Corruption in Vietnam" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corruption_in_Vietnam">high levels of corruption</a>, <a title="Censorship in Vietnam" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Censorship_in_Vietnam">censorship</a>, <a title="Environmental issues in Vietnam" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Environmental_issues_in_Vietnam">environmental issues</a> and a poor <a title="Human rights in Vietnam" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_rights_in_Vietnam">human rights record</a>; the country <a title="International rankings of Vietnam" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_rankings_of_Vietnam">ranks among the lowest</a> in international measurements of <a title="Civil liberties" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Civil_liberties">civil liberties</a>, <a title="Freedom of the press" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_of_the_press">freedom of the press</a>, and <a title="Freedom of religion in Vietnam" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_of_religion_in_Vietnam">freedom of religion and ethnic minorities</a>. It is part of international and intergovernmental institutions including the <a class="mw-redirect" title="Association of Southeast Asian Nations" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Association_of_Southeast_Asian_Nations">ASEAN</a>, the <a title="Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asia-Pacific_Economic_Cooperation">APEC</a>, the <a title="Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comprehensive_and_Progressive_Agreement_for_Trans-Pacific_Partnership">CPTPP</a>, the <a title="Non-Aligned Movement" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-Aligned_Movement">Non-Aligned Movement</a>, the <a title="Organisation internationale de la Francophonie" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Organisation_internationale_de_la_Francophonie">OIF</a>, and the <a title="World Trade Organization" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Trade_Organization">WTO</a>. It has assumed a seat on the <a title="United Nations Security Council" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Nations_Security_Council">United Nations Security Council</a> twice. Mr. Do&#8217;s poem</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/mr-dos-poem/">Mr. Do&#8217;s poem Paper</a> appeared first on <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en">Tin Hay</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/mr-dos-poem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The poem has 8 ways to read</title>
		<link>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/the-poem-has-8-ways-to-read/</link>
					<comments>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/the-poem-has-8-ways-to-read/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[qt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 03:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Good poem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Short story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/?p=59</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a really strange poem. There are up to 8 different readings I love the bright spring scene The pleasures of poetry are filled with wine and cups Flowers placed on bamboo hedges with blue branches The leaves are...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/the-poem-has-8-ways-to-read/">The poem has 8 ways to read</a> appeared first on <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en">Tin Hay</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a really strange poem. There are up to 8 different readings<br />
I love the bright spring scene<br />
The pleasures of poetry are filled with wine and cups<br />
Flowers placed on bamboo hedges with blue branches<br />
The leaves are fragrant with fresh spring fragrance<br />
Passengers go back and forth waiting for the river to calm down<br />
Back and forth the boat waits for a crowded dock<br />
The distant sound of singing and singing is deep<br />
A gentle silhouette with smiling eyes. 2. Read the original lesson backwards from the bottom up (we get lesson 2)<br />
Smiling and smiling with graceful eyes<br />
The bass and bass guitar sing in the distance<br />
People crowded the docks waiting for the boat to go back and forth<br />
The river&#8217;s waves are calm, waiting for guests to pass by<br />
Fresh spring color and scent mixed with leaves<br />
Green bamboo branches hung with flowers on the hedge<br />
Filled with a cup of poetic wine and joy<br />
Bright spring light loves us.<br />
3. Remove the first two words of each sentence in the original lesson (we get lesson 3) (five words and eight sentences, equal rhyme rule)</p>
<p>Bright spring scene<br />
Poetry and wine cups are full<br />
Bamboo hedge with green branches<br />
The fresh scent of spring<br />
Guests wait for the river to calm down<br />
The boat waiting at the dock was crowded with people<br />
The sound of singing is low<br />
A shadow with smiling eyes.<br />
4. Remove the last two words of each sentence in the original lesson, read backwards from the bottom up (we get lesson 4)<br />
(five words, eight sentences, rules in equal rhyme)<br />
Whose eyes are glossy and graceful<br />
The instrument sings in the distance<br />
The dock waits for the boat to go back and forth<br />
The river waits for visitors to cross again<br />
The colors of spring blend with the leaves<br />
Bamboo branches hang flowers on the hedge<br />
A cup of wine and poetic joy<br />
The spring light loves me.<br />
5. Remove the last three words of each sentence in the original lesson (we get lesson 5) (eight sentences &amp; four words)<br />
I love spring scenery<br />
The joy of wine poetry<br />
Flowers installed on bamboo hedges<br />
The leaves blend with the scent of spring<br />
Back and forth, customers wait<br />
Back and forth the boat waits<br />
Far away the sound of singing<br />
Let go of someone&#8217;s shadow.<br />
6. Remove the first three words of each sentence in the original lesson, read backwards from the bottom up (we get lesson 6) (eight sentences &amp; four words)<br />
Smile and smile at someone&#8217;s eyes<br />
Play bass and sing<br />
Crowds of people waiting<br />
The calm waves of the river wait<br />
Fresh spring colors<br />
Green bamboo branches<br />
Fill a cup of wine<br />
Bright spring light.<br />
7. Remove the first four words of each sentence in the original lesson (we get lesson 7) (eight sentences &amp; three words)<br />
Bright light<br />
The cup is full and empty<br />
Blue branches<br />
Bright colors<br />
The river is calm<br />
The wharf is crowded<br />
Bass guitar<br />
Smiling eyes.<br />
8. Remove the last four words of each sentence in the original lesson, read backwards from the bottom up (we get lesson 8) (eight sentences &amp; three words)<br />
Sleek silhouette<br />
Distant hum<br />
The boat goes back and forth<br />
Guests come over again<br />
Fragrance mixed with leaves<br />
Hedge with flowers<br />
Poetry is fun<br />
Canh loves me<a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/mr-dos-poem/">https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/mr-dos-poem/</a></p>
<p><a title="" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vietnamese_language">Vietnamese</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/the-poem-has-8-ways-to-read/">The poem has 8 ways to read</a> appeared first on <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en">Tin Hay</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/the-poem-has-8-ways-to-read/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
