<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Short story Archives - Tin Hay</title>
	<atom:link href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/category/culture/short-story/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/category/culture/short-story/</link>
	<description>Một trang web mới sử dụng WordPress</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 19:31:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The poem has 8 ways to read</title>
		<link>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/the-poem-has-8-ways-to-read/</link>
					<comments>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/the-poem-has-8-ways-to-read/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[qt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 03:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Good poem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Short story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/?p=59</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a really strange poem. There are up to 8 different readings I love the bright spring scene The pleasures of poetry are filled with wine and cups Flowers placed on bamboo hedges with blue branches The leaves are...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/the-poem-has-8-ways-to-read/">The poem has 8 ways to read</a> appeared first on <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en">Tin Hay</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a really strange poem. There are up to 8 different readings<br />
I love the bright spring scene<br />
The pleasures of poetry are filled with wine and cups<br />
Flowers placed on bamboo hedges with blue branches<br />
The leaves are fragrant with fresh spring fragrance<br />
Passengers go back and forth waiting for the river to calm down<br />
Back and forth the boat waits for a crowded dock<br />
The distant sound of singing and singing is deep<br />
A gentle silhouette with smiling eyes. 2. Read the original lesson backwards from the bottom up (we get lesson 2)<br />
Smiling and smiling with graceful eyes<br />
The bass and bass guitar sing in the distance<br />
People crowded the docks waiting for the boat to go back and forth<br />
The river&#8217;s waves are calm, waiting for guests to pass by<br />
Fresh spring color and scent mixed with leaves<br />
Green bamboo branches hung with flowers on the hedge<br />
Filled with a cup of poetic wine and joy<br />
Bright spring light loves us.<br />
3. Remove the first two words of each sentence in the original lesson (we get lesson 3) (five words and eight sentences, equal rhyme rule)</p>
<p>Bright spring scene<br />
Poetry and wine cups are full<br />
Bamboo hedge with green branches<br />
The fresh scent of spring<br />
Guests wait for the river to calm down<br />
The boat waiting at the dock was crowded with people<br />
The sound of singing is low<br />
A shadow with smiling eyes.<br />
4. Remove the last two words of each sentence in the original lesson, read backwards from the bottom up (we get lesson 4)<br />
(five words, eight sentences, rules in equal rhyme)<br />
Whose eyes are glossy and graceful<br />
The instrument sings in the distance<br />
The dock waits for the boat to go back and forth<br />
The river waits for visitors to cross again<br />
The colors of spring blend with the leaves<br />
Bamboo branches hang flowers on the hedge<br />
A cup of wine and poetic joy<br />
The spring light loves me.<br />
5. Remove the last three words of each sentence in the original lesson (we get lesson 5) (eight sentences &amp; four words)<br />
I love spring scenery<br />
The joy of wine poetry<br />
Flowers installed on bamboo hedges<br />
The leaves blend with the scent of spring<br />
Back and forth, customers wait<br />
Back and forth the boat waits<br />
Far away the sound of singing<br />
Let go of someone&#8217;s shadow.<br />
6. Remove the first three words of each sentence in the original lesson, read backwards from the bottom up (we get lesson 6) (eight sentences &amp; four words)<br />
Smile and smile at someone&#8217;s eyes<br />
Play bass and sing<br />
Crowds of people waiting<br />
The calm waves of the river wait<br />
Fresh spring colors<br />
Green bamboo branches<br />
Fill a cup of wine<br />
Bright spring light.<br />
7. Remove the first four words of each sentence in the original lesson (we get lesson 7) (eight sentences &amp; three words)<br />
Bright light<br />
The cup is full and empty<br />
Blue branches<br />
Bright colors<br />
The river is calm<br />
The wharf is crowded<br />
Bass guitar<br />
Smiling eyes.<br />
8. Remove the last four words of each sentence in the original lesson, read backwards from the bottom up (we get lesson 8) (eight sentences &amp; three words)<br />
Sleek silhouette<br />
Distant hum<br />
The boat goes back and forth<br />
Guests come over again<br />
Fragrance mixed with leaves<br />
Hedge with flowers<br />
Poetry is fun<br />
Canh loves me<a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/mr-dos-poem/">https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/mr-dos-poem/</a></p>
<p><a title="" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vietnamese_language">Vietnamese</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/the-poem-has-8-ways-to-read/">The poem has 8 ways to read</a> appeared first on <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en">Tin Hay</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/the-poem-has-8-ways-to-read/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best friend</title>
		<link>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/best-friend/</link>
					<comments>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/best-friend/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[qt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 03:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Art of Living]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beautiful life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Short story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/?p=57</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Terror filled the heart of a World War I soldier when he saw his lifelong friend fall in battle. Trapped in a trench and artillery shells flying continuously overhead, the soldier asked his commander to allow him to go out...</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/best-friend/">Best friend</a> appeared first on <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en">Tin Hay</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Terror filled the heart of a World War I soldier when he saw his lifelong friend fall in battle.<br />
Trapped in a trench and artillery shells flying continuously overhead, the soldier asked his commander to allow him to go out into the &#8220;plain area&#8221; between the trenches to bring back his wounded comrade.</p>
<p>The commander said:</p>
<p>&#8211; You can go but I think the job won&#8217;t be worth it. Perhaps his friend was dead and he could lose his own life.</p>
<p>Regardless of the commander&#8217;s words, the soldier still left. Miraculously, he managed to reach his friend, lifted him onto his shoulders, and carried him back to their trench. As they both tumbled into the trench, the commander checked on the hit soldier and then looked sympathetically at his friend.</p>
<p>-I told you, that job is not worth it. &#8211; The commander said &#8211; Your friend is dead, and you are seriously injured.</p>
<p>The soldier replied:</p>
<p>&#8211; Even so, the job is still worth doing, boss.</p>
<p>&#8211; What do you mean by worth doing? Your friend is dead, right?</p>
<p>-Boss, it was worth doing because when I got to him, he was still alive and I was very satisfied when he told me &#8220;Jim, I knew that you would definitely come to me!&#8221;</p>
<p>In life, whether something is worth doing or not depends entirely on how we look at it. Be courageous and do what your heart tells you so that later in life you won&#8217;t have to regret not doing it. Hopefully each and every one of us will be in the true arms of such friends.<a title="" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vietnamese_language">Vietnamese</a><a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/mr-dos-poem/">https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/mr-dos-poem/</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/best-friend/">Best friend</a> appeared first on <a href="https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en">Tin Hay</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://tuvo123.github.io/tinhay4/en/best-friend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
